Guide to the Cornwall Natural History Collection 1888-1982 MS 023 MS 023 MS 023
Cornwall Historical Society
Cornwall Natural History Collection
1888-1982
Cornwall Historical Society
MS 023
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
This collection contains items related to Cornwall’s natural history.
Provenance
The collection was created from loose items found in miscellaneous boxes.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The majority of items in this collection are associated with weather-related events, especially the 1955 flood that devastated much of western Connecticut. Documents donated by Andrew C. Pikosky detailing the 1906 trapping of a wildcat by Stanley Joray are also included.
Sources:
Scope and Content Note
This collection is divided into two series, one devoted to weather patterns and the other to wildlife, and organized chronologically within those sections.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged chronologically within each series.
The files are grouped into 2 series:
Weather
Wildlife
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Cornwall (Conn.); Articles; Cornwall Historical Society; Pikosky, Andrew C.; Joray, Stanley
- Weather
  - Article, “A Genuine ‘Blizzard!’” in Connecticut Western News, 1888 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Newspaper clipping about New Madrid, MO earthquake, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Article, “Flood Inundates Litchfield County Areas,” in The Lakeville Journal, 1949 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Poster showing flood damage in Winsted, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Waterbury Republican with stories on flood damage, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Lakeville Journal with stories on flood damage, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The August Flood: A Special Edition of the Beacon, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Western Connecticut’s Great Flood Disaster: August 19, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Wildlife
  - Items donated by Andrew C. Pikosky related to Stanley Joray trapping a wildcat, 1906-1982; , undated (Box 1, Folder 11-Sep)